# Guilherme Nunes Trofino

• guitrofino@gmail.com • LinkedIn: guilherme-trofino • GitHub: tr0fin0 • +33 07 49 18 55 00

## Summary

I'm Guilherme, a 22-year-old Brazilian student from the Campinas State University - UNICAMP, pursuing since 2022 a 3-year double degree exchange program at ENSTA Paris. There I've been enrolled in their Information and Communication Sciences and Technologies master's degree with robotics as chosen emphasis.

Now I'm half-way through a gap year looking for a 5-month internship available from the 25th of March until the 9th of September in Business Management, Product / Project Management, or Data Analysis to complement my engineering formation.

## Experience

**Amazon France** CLICHY, FRANCE

# Retail Vendor Manager Intern

09/2023 - 03/2024

In collaboration with a Senior Vendor Manager, I helped provide tools designed to optimize business performance and drive sales growth. This included a user-friendly Excel macro designed to quickly identify licensed selection, allowing deep dives in large datasets, uncovering trends, extracting customer insights, and taking action.

I also developed a comprehensive and visually appealing Dashboard in Excel, facilitating benchmarking at various levels of granularity, simplifying the identification of growth opportunities and the implementation of new strategies for the team.

## ISIR, Sorbonne Université

Paris, France

#### Neuroscience Research Intern

05/2023 - 08/2023

Developing a user-friendly simulation environment using Webots and Python, facilitating the assessment of the sensorimotor modelization of the hippocampus based on the framework proposed by Benoît Girard and Sylvain Argentieri.

## Phoenix Robotics Team of UNICAMP

CAMPINAS, BRAZIL

Established in 2001 by mechatronics engineering students, the Phoenix Robotic Team had, in 2022, 83 undergraduate students from different courses designing, building, and competing with autonomous and radio-controlled robots across 12 categories.

**Head of Team** 

Definition of long-term planning for the Team's departments and projects aiming for sustainable growth, resulting in a new people-driven culture and mission setting short and medium-term targets and deadlines for the 5 area coordinators and the 12 project coordinators.

Improve Team Members' selection process, aiming for more diversity, resulting in the best inscription ratio, over 125 people from 500, and resulting in the best percentage of women among the approved, 16 from 35 people.

#### **Head of Electronics Department**

08/2020 - 07/2021

During this timeframe, we closed a strategic partnership with Altium, securing access to Altium Designer and Altium 365, and we implemented a 10-week project-based training program, onboarding 12 people to the team.

#### **Education**

ENSTA Paris, IP Paris

Palaiseau, France

THE Ranking includes the Institut Polytechnique de Paris among the Top 80 universities with the best reputation in the world with about 40% of international students, research and faculty members and 10 education fields.

#### Master of Science Engineering - M1 Computer Science

07/2022 - Present

M1 in Computer Science with emphasis in Robotics in a double degree program with UNICAMP.

## FEM, UNICAMP

Campinas, Brazil

THE Ranking includes UNICAMP among universities with the best reputation in the world with approximately 34000 students enrolled in 66 undergraduate courses and 153 postgraduate programmes.

## Bachelor in Control and Automation Engineering - Mechatronics

03/2019 - Present

## Skills

#### Languages

# Softwares

1. Portuguese: Native 2. English: Advanced, C1

- 1. Coding: C, LaTeX, MATLAB, Python and VBA
- 2. Operating Systems: Linux and Windows
- 3. Office: Excel, PowerPoint and Word
- 4. Others: Altium, Illustrator and Photoshop

3. French: Advanced, C1

# Guilherme Nunes Trofino

• guitrofino@gmail.com • LinkedIn: guilherme-trofino • GitHub: tr0fin0 • +33 07 49 18 55 00

## Summary

I'm Guilherme, a 22-year-old Brazilian student from the Campinas State University - UNICAMP, pursuing since 2022 a 3-year double degree exchange program at ENSTA Paris. There I've been enrolled in their Information and Communication Sciences and Technologies master's degree with robotics as chosen emphasis.

Now I'm half-way through a gap year looking for a 5-month internship available from the 25th of March until the 9th of September in Business Management, Product / Project Management, or Data Analysis to complement my engineering formation.

## Experience

**Amazon France** CLICHY, FRANCE

# Retail Vendor Manager Intern

09/2023 - 03/2024

In collaboration with a Senior Vendor Manager, I helped provide tools designed to optimize business performance and drive sales growth. This included a user-friendly Excel macro designed to quickly identify licensed selection, allowing deep dives in large datasets, uncovering trends, extracting customer insights, and taking action.

I also developed a comprehensive and visually appealing Dashboard in Excel, facilitating benchmarking at various levels of granularity, simplifying the identification of growth opportunities and the implementation of new strategies for the team.

## ISIR, Sorbonne Université

Paris, France

#### Neuroscience Research Intern

05/2023 - 08/2023

Developing a user-friendly simulation environment using Webots and Python, facilitating the assessment of the sensorimotor modelization of the hippocampus based on the framework proposed by Benoît Girard and Sylvain Argentieri.

## Phoenix Robotics Team of UNICAMP

CAMPINAS, BRAZIL

Established in 2001 by mechatronics engineering students, the Phoenix Robotic Team had, in 2022, 83 undergraduate students from different courses designing, building, and competing with autonomous and radio-controlled robots across 12 categories.

**Head of Team** 

Definition of long-term planning for the Team's departments and projects aiming for sustainable growth, resulting in a new people-driven culture and mission setting short and medium-term targets and deadlines for the 5 area coordinators and the 12 project coordinators.

Improve Team Members' selection process, aiming for more diversity, resulting in the best inscription ratio, over 125 people from 500, and resulting in the best percentage of women among the approved, 16 from 35 people.

#### **Head of Electronics Department**

08/2020 - 07/2021

During this timeframe, we closed a strategic partnership with Altium, securing access to Altium Designer and Altium 365, and we implemented a 10-week project-based training program, onboarding 12 people to the team.

#### **Education**

ENSTA Paris, IP Paris

Palaiseau, France

THE Ranking includes the Institut Polytechnique de Paris among the Top 80 universities with the best reputation in the world with about 40% of international students, research and faculty members and 10 education fields.

#### Master of Science Engineering - M1 Computer Science

07/2022 - Present

M1 in Computer Science with emphasis in Robotics in a double degree program with UNICAMP.

## FEM, UNICAMP

Campinas, Brazil

THE Ranking includes UNICAMP among universities with the best reputation in the world with approximately 34000 students enrolled in 66 undergraduate courses and 153 postgraduate programmes.

## Bachelor in Control and Automation Engineering - Mechatronics

03/2019 - Present

## Skills

#### Languages

# Softwares

1. Portuguese: Native 2. English: Advanced, C1

- 1. Coding: C, LaTeX, MATLAB, Python and VBA
- 2. Operating Systems: Linux and Windows
- 3. Office: Excel, PowerPoint and Word
- 4. Others: Altium, Illustrator and Photoshop

3. French: Advanced, C1